#### JEREMY GUAN

22/40-46 Station Road, Auburn, Sydney, NSW 2144 Mobile: 0423700188 Email: jeremy.guan@gmail.com

I am a Sydney-based software and web developer with five years industry experience. With a wide range of skills in software and web application development, I have worked in a number of different projects for a variety of clients. My specialties include open source and web technologies, such as Perl/Python/Ruby, JavaScript/jQuery, MySQL/PostgreSQL and Linux. Moreover, I always keep an open mind and am eager to learn new technologies to enhance my career and professional growth.

TECHNICAL OVERVIEW				
Languages	Perl (5 yrs)	PHP (1 yr)	Python (<1 yr)*	Ruby (<1 yr)*
	Java (2 yrs)	C (1 yr)	C++ (2 yrs)	C# (1 yr)
	JavaScript (4 yrs)			
Databases	MySQL (4 yrs)	PostgreSQL (1 yr)	SQL Server (1 yr)	Oracle (1 yr)
Frameworks	Catalyst (5 yrs)	ASP.NET (1 yr)	Rails (<1 yr)*	Django (<1 yr)*
Web	HTML/CSS (10+ yrs)	HTML5/CSS3 (1 yr)*	jQuery (4 yrs)	
Tools	Apache (5 yrs)	Subversion (5 yrs)	Git (<1 yr)*	Vim (5 yrs)
		* Learning in progress		

WORK EXPERIENCE

October 2006 - Current

**Software Systems Developer** at dbNet Pty Ltd (http://dbnet.com.au), full-time.

At dbNet, I have played significant roles in the following major Projects and/or Clients:

# • NSW Govt: Roads & Traffic Authority (February 2011 – Current)

- Designed and developed web-based School Zone Alert System (SZAS) management application
- o Technology/Application used:
  - Linux openSUSE
  - Apache / mod\_perl
  - PostgreSQL
  - Perl / POE / Catalyst / Template Toolkit / Class::DBI
  - JavaScript / jQuery
  - HTML/XHTML/CSS

### • ADmira (January 2010 – October 2010)

- Designed and developed web-based Active Directory management system (http://dbnet.com.au/ADmira/)
- Technology / Applications used:
  - Windows Servers / IIS
  - C# / ASP.NET
  - JavaScript / jQuery

- jqTouch / iWebkit
- HTML5

### • Wireless Sensors Australia (January 2009 – April 2009)

- Developer for "Lifeguard" data visualisation web application (http://dbnet.com.au:82/lifeguard/home)
- o Technology / Applications used:
  - Linux / Apache
  - Perl / Catalyst
  - JavaScript / jQuery / Ajax
  - Google Chart Tools
  - MODBUS Protocol
  - Spinwave A3 and Energy Management Wireless Sensor family

## • MF Global Australia Pty Ltd (August 2007 – Current)

- Designed and developed commercial website with both client facing and back-office billing functionality (https://my.mfglobal.com.au/)
- o Technology / Applications used:
  - Linux openSUSE
  - MySql
  - Perl / Catalyst
  - HTML / XHTML / CSS
  - Javascript / JQuery
  - SOAP/XML

### • NSW Govt: Office of the Director of Public Prosecutions (NSW) (May 2007)

- Technology/Application used:
  - Objective CMS / ISYS Search Engine
  - Visual Studio C++
  - Perl / CPAN modules
  - HTML / XHTML / CSS / JavaScript

# • NSW Govt: Dust Diseases Board (October 2006 – May 2007, currently on Maintenance Contract)

- o Technology / Applications used:
  - Linux openSUSE
  - Perl / Catalyst
  - Subversion
  - T-SQL with MS SQL Sever 2005
  - WebDav and VBA for MS Word and web application integration

### July 2001 - October 2003

Webmaster at MyDrivers.com (http://www.mydrivers.com), full-time.

The responsibilities are to administered and maintained the high-traffic primary website and mirror sites.

# **EDUCATION**

Master of Computer Studies with **Distinction**, University of Wollongong, December 2005 Bachelor of Civil Engineering, ZhengZhou University (China), July 2001

# **CERTIFICATIONS**

- Sun Certified Programmer for the Java 2 Platform, 2006
- Microsoft Certified Database Administrator, 2002
- Microsoft Certified System Engineer, 2002

# REFEREES

Available upon request